Jim Newpower

Software Engineer

2757 S Langley Ct Denver CO 80210 jimnewpower@gmail.com 303<u>.870.4369</u>

Engineer with over 25 years combined experience in the software industry. Dedicated developer with diverse skill set and creativity who delivers reliable software through test-driven and agile methods. Proficient in multiple languages and frameworks, excelling in small, collaborative teams.

Expert in Java API (through version 10), including all of the latest enhancements (streams, lambdas, multithreading, etc.).

Qualifications

- ° Java, C/C++, C#, SQL, Python, PHP, HTML/CSS, Javascript, UML
- ° .NET, Swing, Android, Web
- ° Git, Visual Studio, Eclipse, Android Studio, Gerrit, Jenkins,
- Rally, Jira, Enterprise Architect
- ° JUnit, Apache Commons, Guava, Jide, OpenGL

- ° Multithreading/Parallel Processing
- ° Triangulation Algorithms
- ° Database transaction/management system
- ° Agile, Test Driven, Clean Code
- ° ACM and IEEE member
- ° Agile, Test Driven, Clean Code, SOLID

Experience

2008-Present: Platte River Associates, Inc.

Software Engineering Director

- ° Architect and develop flagship geologic modeling applications
- ° Analyze big data with statistics, histograms, radar charts, cross plots, regression, etc.
- Manipulate and visualize large scientific datasets from seismic surveys/well logs
- ° Leverage multicore for simulations, large datasets, visualization, etc.
- ° SQL database back-end
- ° Implement Gridding and Contouring algorithms
- ° Import and export well known file types for ArcGIS, Petrosys, Zycor, Surfer, etc.
- ° Work with clients and stakeholders to continually improve software

2010-Present: Prima Technologies, Ltd.

Founder and Principal Engineer

- ° Android internals contract to improve Android OS modification for Spectralink handhelds
- ° Barcode scanner, SIP, Push to Talk
- ° EliteDraft Android fantasy football draft application (over 13,000 unique installs)
- ° Manage live drafts, push draft picks to website for live updates/analysis

1993-2008: Platte River Associates, Inc.

Software Engineer

- ° Develop and maintain existing software
- ° Implement new graphics system
- $^{\circ}$ Ports: Linux to Windows, 16 to 32-bits, C to C++, C++ to Java

Achievements and Interests

Sponsored 2 Senior Software Engineering projects at University of Colorado:

- ° Seeing Another Dimension (SAD), a 3-D visualization application
- ° Sparkle Magic API for Graphics (SMAG), a pure Java 2-D graphics system
- ° Family time
- ° Skiing
- ° Hiking
- ° Photography
- ° Cooking
- ° Building things

Education

Bachelor of Science Computer Science (Engineering) University of Colorado 1992

- ° Computer Performance Modeling
- ° Artificial Intelligence, Computer Architecture
- ° Electrical Engineering, Algorithms
- ° Software Engineering Senior Project
- ° Calculus I,II,III, Physics, Probability & Statistics
- ° Data Structures, Graphics, Languages